To see you.
>> Good morning, Ted. Good to see you, bud.
We are we are deprogram with Ted Rall
and John Kiriakou. We're here every
Monday through Friday, 9:00 a.m. Eastern
time.
Thank you for liking, following, and
sharing the show. Uh we are as usual
ready to go. We've got producer Robbie
West bringing up the rear in about 30
minutes. In the meantime, you'll have to
put up with my incompetent use of the
board. But Robbie did school me on how
to try to avoid packet loss. Uh so
hopefully whatever that is, I don't even
know. Uh they threw me out of
engineering school.
Um and with good reason. I think that
was like one of the you know, better
thing one of the better bad things that
happened to me that was good for
society. You would never want to drive
across a bridge that I designed. Um
okay, so let's let's move on. We have
lots to talk about. Please uh you know,
as usual, chime in with your questions
and comments if you're watching live on
Rumble or YouTube. And thank you for
doing that. By the way, um if you want
to comment, we are thinking about
possibly figuring out a way to take
voice calls. Um so uh if that's
something that sounds stupid or annoying
or sounds great, um you know, we'd love
to hear your opinions about that. Um
Ukraine uh it looks it looks like um uh
Trump is turning his attention to the
conflict there. Um there's a 28-point
plan that appears to be gaining some
traction in light of domestic uh events
there in Ukraine. We'll get into that.
Um there's a special military delegation
on their on route to Kyiv. Um so they're
there. Um
And then John, there's a story that I'm
sure you'll have some Robert Hansen
related thoughts um about uh the an FBI
whistleblower has stepped forward. Um
you know, you you you helped um inspire
a lot more whistle whistleblowers have
occurred as a result. Um anyway, it
turns out that this is kind of crazy.
When I read the story, I was like, wait,
what? So uh basically the FBI has
decided that they they they have they
have a counterespionage cell which is in
charge of looking for moles. And but you
know, they're exempting the executives.
Yes. So you know, cuz after all, it's
not like a high-ranking executive of the
FBI has ever
been a mole. Oh, never, right? Never
never would that happen.
Man, let me ask you for a second.
Please.
>> to a I went to an event last night. Uh
it was a book launch for the two IRS
whistleblowers who blew the whistle on
um
on uh Hunter Biden's
uh income tax evasion.
Right? They were specifically told,
"Don't look at the laptop."
And they're like,
"What are they crazy, their bosses? Of
course we're going to look at the
laptop." And they found that he spent
$10,000 at a sex club and tried to write
it off as a deduction um
line iteming line iteming it as um golf
club membership.
Right? A golf country club membership.
It was a sex club. He spent $10,000 in
one night in a sex club. I was going to
say like how much sex can one man have?
Well, when you're on that much meth, I
can see having $6,000
>> [laughter]
>> in one night. When you're on that much
meth, but the reason I'm bringing this
up is
first of all, these guys were very kind
to me last night. And Brad Birkenfeld
was there. There are a bunch of
whistleblowers and that we inspired them
to go public. They knew it was going to
cost them their careers.
Um
but Senator Grassley was there.
Chairman Comer was there. Chairman
Jordan was there. And the Secretary of
the Treasury
Becent was there.
And I'll tell you what, man, when I blew
the whistle on the torture program, I
stood alone.
And now the fact that there are all
these political people saying,
"You know, it's unacceptable to treat
whistleblowers this way."
I loved it. Now, the bad
>> need a shield law. We still need a
shield law.
And and the bad part of this is every
one of those people I just mentioned is
um
is a Republican.
I It looks like I froze. Doggone it.
Yeah, we can hear you. Oh, good.
>> Okay, there you are. Okay. Um every one
of those people was a Republican that I
just mentioned. There were no Democrats
there at all. No Democrats at all. And
then as it so happened,
>> in 1979 that being the case? Ridiculous.
As it so happened, while I was there, I
got a call from not from Fox News. And
they asked if I would go over to the
studio and do a hit at 8:30 on the Jesse
Watters show. I said, "Sure, what do you
want me to talk about?" And they said,
"We want you to talk about this
advertisement
that the Democrats, six Democratic
members of Congress, have come out with
led by Elissa Slotkin,
the former CIA analyst who I used to
work with on Iraq. Um she's now a
senator from Michigan.
Uh they did this advertisement
geared directly at the military
saying, "Remember, you have to disobey
an illegal order. You have to disobey.
Be strong. Disobey illegal orders." This
is just a a shot at Trump, right? Cuz
they want people to believe that Trump
is going to refuse to leave the White
House. It's ridiculous. It's because the
Democrats don't stand for anything that
they're doing something like this. So
Slotkin and I happened to be walking in
the building at the same time. I said,
"Hi, Elissa." And she just looks at me
and then turns her head. And I was like,
"Okay."
That just made me
Ted, it made me so angry. I went on Fox
and I eviscerated her and the Democrats.
So I go on and
>> Rightly so. I said, "Why do you think"
He says to me, "Why do you think the
Democrats are doing this?"
And I said uh
"Because they have no ideas.
And because they stand for nothing.
Uh this is the whole Democratic
platform. It's vote for me because I'm
not the other guy. I say it all the time
on my own show." I said, "Vote for me
because I'm not the other guy." And I
said, "And how rich is it?
Excuse me, cuz I'm in a bad mood this
morning.
It's okay. It's more fun for us.
How rich is it that when I was arrested
after blowing the whistle on the illegal
and immoral torture program, it was the
Democrats that went after me,
not the Republicans. But now they want
everybody to refuse to follow illegal
orders.
No, it's it's it's bad. Um John, let me
pur a propos of that. Um
so I had a job interview at Vox, and
which is a democratically Yeah. oriented
uh you know, news site. This was a
several years ago.
And they told And and basically um I had
done a piece
they had commissioned a cartoon
journalism piece for me.
And in that and anyway, long story
short, in that said, I said uh something
about like the CIA claims that. And they
said, "Oh, we have a problem with that."
It's like, "We in it is our editorial
policy." my editor told me, "that
anything the Intelligence Committee says
is taken as fact Oh my god. And I said,
"What?" And I'm like and I'm like, you
know, I'm I'm sorry. I'm old school. I
think if my if your mother says she
loves you, you check it out. Um you
know, it's it you're journalist. You
don't take anyone.
And besides which, the CIA's job is in
many cases to dissemble and lie. I mean,
it's they should. They have to. Um
and so
he was like, "But anyway, the point is
of the story is not to complain about
the corruption of Vox, but really the
point is democratically
things have changed, right? When you
have um Democrats acting the way you
describe, Democratic journalists um
acting the way I describe. I mean, the
Democrats climbed in up the ass of the
intelligence community.
Um
why and how did that happen? Cuz I
didn't notice it happening, you know,
before it happened or while it was
happening.
Yeah, that's a good question. You know,
it it used to be when nobody from the
CIA would ever run for elected office
unless they'd been in the CIA for a
minute and then decided it wasn't for
them. Like Porter Goss. Porter Goss was
in the CIA for for 4 years. He was a
failed case officer. He moved to
Florida, became a a multimillionaire
real estate developer, and then got
himself elected to Congress,
became chairman of the Intelligence
Committee, and then went back to be an
absolutely terrible
um like historically terrible uh CIA
director. But
but time was when that was really highly
unusual. And now it seems like people at
the CIA like everybody envisions himself
as or herself as governor of Virginia or
a member of Congress. I remember when
Will Hurd uh
resigned to run for Congress, I said,
"Will,
you know, that's not really a step up
to run for Congress.
What are you doing?"
And he ran and he won. He won. He won
three terms.
>> He tried to recruit me to run for
Congress, and I told him the same thing.
Yeah. Will won three terms. Stepped
down. Yeah. And then
uh and then quit.
Yeah.
He realized. Thanks uh so for the dollar
and and the comment. Also, thanks to
Hyperneurotic for the $2 and the advice
about avoiding packet loss, which I
still don't really understand. All
right, here's a question for you, John.
Okay.
>> this is from Fwa as I'm going to
pronounce it, 6624.
Um when an when an agency recruits
someone as high level as a president,
how do you keep them in check? I would
think that they don't need the money
anymore. An example would be Jelani.
That's a great question. And it's a
rather important question.
>> [clears throat]
>> Nine times out of 10,
you actually recruit the person when
they're a junior level nobody, and then
they rise through the system and they
become president or prime minister or
defense minister or foreign minister.
When that happens, you just kind of put
them on ice. You cut off contact
uh, while they're president or prime
minister. And if they have something
important to say,
they'll ask to see the US ambassador.
The US ambassador knows that's a signal
to bring you along, and then you collect
the intelligence while the ambassador
pretends not to listen in the corner of
the room. Otherwise, if it's somebody
like
Jelani, for example,
um,
or now we know
Hamid Karzai, Mhm. the the CIA station
chief just
goes straight into the office and, you
know,
does the meeting.
You know, suitcases full of money and
and all that good stuff.
>> do you keep them in How do you keep that
person, you know, How do How do you run
them without them getting out of
control?
>> [sighs]
>> Well,
look at Manuel Noriega. He went out of
control. And you see what the US
response was. The US response was to
essentially overthrow him, kidnap him,
occupy his country, and put him in
prison for the rest of his life. And
that's really what it comes out to. It's
like you're fired. Uh, thanks Toby for
the two Australian dollars and the
thought. Agree, pardon John. Uh, Marble,
thanks for the $4.99.
Swirling green indeed.
Swirling green is people. Just remember
that. It's very important to remember
that. Thanks for the five bucks to 7371.
Mojor, just heard uh, first heard about
the Huckabee Pollard story from you guys
first, and also Pod Save America. It's
not in any of my news apps. Why do you
think that is?
See,
That's a good question.
>> [clears throat]
>> That is a good question. It's always,
like I say, it's never about what they
say. It's Well, it's usually not about
what they say. It's usually about what
they don't say.
Yeah.
Yeah, uh, what It should be. It should
be on the on the, you know, above the
fold page one of every of every news
publication in America today. And and
you're right, it's not. Moro, thanks for
the five bucks. Any thoughts on doing a
live show and meet or meet and greet in
the New York New Jersey area? I'd be
totally down. So would I. I would do
that.
Yeah. I I'll be there. Sure. I mean, I'm
local. Um, Yeah, I I'd love to do that.
Fasmatas, I am very sorry, but John
already did the Alec Baldwin story
yesterday. You just go back over on
Rumble and he you can listen to it over
there.
Uh,
so,
yeah. Um, thanks for the dollar FU so
Democrats are the Seinfeld party, a
party about nothing. That's funny.
Oh, that's good. Oh, I wish I had
thought of that.
>> But that would be more entertaining.
Yeah, that would be more entertaining.
But that But that's a really great, um,
one-liner. I think I might steal that.
Who said that? Uh, who Sorry, I'm I'm
I'm scrolling.
>> Oh, sorry. Sorry. Okay, that's okay. Uh,
it's it's FU so.
Excellent. That's That's excellent, FU
so. I'm going to I'm going to take that.
That is very very funny. Um,
okay.
Uh, well, some criticism. You complain
about them not standing up for anything,
says Sneaker Dad. But And when you do,
you complain.
I don't know what what Really?
Be more specific, please. I I I don't
see that one.
Uh, here, I'll put it back up.
>> Okay, thanks.
I'm sorry. I'm like having
This is is so hard to Here we go. I'm
putting it up. It's up.
Thanks.
Uh, I still don't see it, but that's
okay. I'll find it. Oh, it's You have to
be watching on like,
I guess, on Rumble.
Okay, on Rumble.
>> I'm watching I'm doing this through
Rumble Studio. Okay.
Um, thanks Ray, about the comment about
my cartoon. Yeah, I was pretty pleased
with that. I didn't know if that It's
about pointing out the fact that, uh,
you know, food stamps are back, but all
the food stamps are going to do is allow
people to buy more [__] craps crap food
that's going to give them
health problems that they're not going
to be able to pay for by going to go to
the doctor.
Um, May I interrupt for 1 second?
>> Please. Now, I'm right now seeing
Sneaker Dad. I complain about them not
standing up for anything, and when they
do, I complain. What do they stand for?
Yeah, that's Literally, name one thing
that the Democrats have actually stood
up for.
I'm I'm waiting. I told you I I've said
in the past, I was a third generation
Democrat.
And when they turned into the
Republicans, I walked.
And And now they're worse than the
Republicans. I My mom took me door to
door,
you know, leafleting pamphleteering for
George McGovern in 1972.
And I worked for Democratic campaigns. I
was youth coordinator for Dukakis in
1988. Um, you know, I mean, I was a I
was a as Democrat as they come. I was
true blue. But I'm with you, John. They
don't [__] stand for They're
Republicans now. Yeah, they're
Republicans. Especially on these foreign
peace issues. FU so wants to know from
How much is the CIA involved in the
color revolution in Mexico against the
socialist president?
I've received a couple of emails from
friends in Mexico about this. And
I would have to say that
that they probably are involved. Um,
just because this thing looks
too perfectly set up. I I I don't have
any evidence on which to base that. Mhm.
But, uh,
but it looks like, uh, something's going
on in Mexico. And there's a There's also
a question from, um, I just saw it.
From, um,
Well, there are two. Uh, one from Shawn
Whitman.
Uh, I've been watching you for a year.
Love your insight. Thank you. A recent
post by, uh, The Majority Report says
Trump may have been an FBI informant. Do
you think this is possible? Absolutely.
Absolutely possible. Because, listen,
99.9 times out of 100,
when the FBI goes to someone and says,
"We're the FBI.
We're doing an investigation and we need
your help." They're going to say, "Of
course, I'll help. I'm a patriotic
American. Of course, I'll help the FBI."
And so, over the course of all those
years, with Trump bumping up against
organized crime in New York, for
example,
um,
foreign
oligarchs and billionaires,
absolutely. I would be shocked if he had
not been a source for the FBI.
Now, that's That's an interesting Yeah,
well, that's a good point, right? Now,
he's he definitely was so crime adjacent
that
>> Yes. Yes.
Um, Greg,
thanks so much for the five bucks. And
they said He said he would fly out to a
meet and greet with John.
>> Well, I I would totally
>> just take the bus.
>> [laughter]
>> I would totally do that. We should set
it up. All right. Well, hey, listen. By
the way, you know, if you guys if any if
you're listening or watching and you
have access to a venue that could
sponsor an appearance by John, me, both
of us, one of us, um, you know, just
reach out to us.
We can, you know, we we need What we
always need is a sponsor We need a venue
and ideally an honorarium. Um, and and
and transportation. And that's not so
hard. People will do that. People can
make money by having us come out. I
mean, you know, it's like they can sell
tickets and they can make a profit. I
mean, you know, that's fine, you know,
so it's That's how this used to work. I
don't know why it's so complicated now.
Seriously. Uh, anyway, um,
here we go. Phil says, and I disagree
with this, but I want to put up stuff
that I put up stuff that I disagree
with. It's my understanding that the
Dems lost their old school base when
they went way left. That's when they
lost the moderates, their long-term
supporters. We
>> Well, I I would strongly disagree with
that. I I think they went way right.
They walked away from organized labor.
They embraced wars of choice. I think
they moved
solidly to the right. That's That's
That's my take as well. I think what
really happened is they started chasing
corporate contributions
in the '90s. I mean, Bernie Sanders
talks about this
quite eloquently and at length, and I
think extremely credibly. And I think
that's what happened. And then like once
you start to take their money, you have
to take their calls and you have to do
what they want.
Moro, thanks for the $4.99. Any thoughts
on Sorry, we already have that one.
Tobby J, five thanks for the five bucks.
Any Any thoughts on Candace Owens
investigating Charlie Kirk's death? Uh,
I touched on this yesterday.
>> Yeah, uh,
I I really want to like Candace Owens
since she's come around on Palestine,
but she's just so nutty. And
she makes these wild accusations like
the Egyptian military following Charlie
Kirk's wife.
They're not based on anything. There's
no evidence of any of this stuff that
she's saying. So, I don't I wouldn't
even call this an investigation. I would
call
>> That's what I would say. Yeah. It's just
bullshitting. It's just talking.
>> Yeah.
It's It's spitballing is what it is.
>> I like that. Um, all right. So, should
we talk about Ukraine? I mean, obviously
this is a story that um has been going
on uh long enough that you and I were in
very different places of employment and
places in our lives when it all started.
And uh you know, and it's kind of still
in a weird way surprising to me that it
ever came to that and that it and and
that it's still grinding on. There's so
much about it that surprises me and also
how this became this crazy cause célèbre
and I mean like go on and on. I I It's
It's weird to me that the Ukrainians
provoked it. It's weird to me that the
Russians allowed themselves to be
provoked. It's weird to me that the
Russians didn't close the deal. It's
weird that the entire Western world
decided to make this the hill that they
wanted to have their economy die on. The
whole thing is weird. Um, that they
Nord Stream is weird, how it went down,
all the whole thing. But anyway, so
currently Zelenskyy, we've talked about
this, everybody who listens to this show
knows that he has this uh buddy, Timur
Mindich, uh who's basically
uh basically running like the Enron of
Ukraine and causing rolling blockouts
and he's uh you know, he and his minions
are basically suspected of stealing at
least 100 million people, uh maybe more
from the from Ukraine. And so so far
Zelenskyy himself has
dollars, right? From the investigation.
Um
but um you know, Zelenskyy is obviously
politically weak. He's He's back on his
heels right now. And so a lot of people
are speculating and I kind of agree with
their speculation that Trump used this
as an opportunity to kind of uh push
through a deal that otherwise Ukraine
might not agree to. And basically it's
the deal that we kind of know all along.
It's mostly a deal that favors Russia um
where the existing lines Now, John,
what's happening is the existing lines
are kind of the Ukrainians accept that
they've lost that territory and it's
never coming back. Now, they're saying
that they don't want to loot seed
additional territory [clears throat]
that is not yet under Russian control.
Right.
Isn't this exactly what we have all said
from the very beginning that the that
the Ukrainians are going to have to walk
away from the territory where where um
most people are native Russian speakers.
So, Donetsk and Luhansk, they're going
to have to walk away from Crimea, which
has only been Ukrainian since like 1953
anyway. Right.
>> We've all said that from the very
beginning. And they couldn't join NATO,
but they could join fast track um the
European Union. And that's exactly what
this thing's going to turn out to be.
>> missiles and and not maybe
demilitarization, but reduced
militarization. By the way, that's
Russia and the US doing Ukraine a favor.
I wish someone would tell the US to cut
its military in half so that we could
start feeding the homeless. Seriously.
Um Totally agree. So, I mean like if you
know, you don't want to be like North
Korea where all of your resources go
into the military. Um
But anyway, so all right. So, how this
looks like obviously the Trump
administration is putting some oomph
behind it, right? They're sending the
Secretary of the Army and a and General
Randy George off to to Kyiv to That's a
big deal. It's a big deal, right? So, it
seems to me like uh and we had Trump
today uh or yesterday saying, "You know,
I've already I've already fixed eight
wars. I should now I'm working on the
ninth one." So funny. [snorts]
Uh I mean, maybe tell the Palestinians
who keep getting blown up every day.
>> Yeah, he confuses ceasefires for, you
know, the ends of of wars. Yeah, they're
not definitely not the same thing. Um
but you know, I mean look, ceasefires
are always appreciated, but
nevertheless. So, all right. So, what
happens now? Um I mean, it looks like
Zelenskyy is
chastened. It looks like he's more I
mean, but on the other hand, you never
know with him cuz he's such a weasel. Um
you know, over you know, over the last
year or so, we've seen him go from like,
"Oh, no, I'm I'm serious about peace."
to "But I'm only serious about peace if
I don't have to give up any territory at
all." Right.
You know, the thing about Zelenskyy, I
I think he he's at the point now where
he's wondering number one, if he can
make it to the end of the Trump
administration, which he can't. There's
We have 3 years to go.
And number two, even if he could,
will another Republican win and put him
out of business or will a Democrat come
in and rescue him and save him? I I
learned just recently that he actually
owns a home in Greece. I I've been
thinking that he would end up in in
London. Um
but he's got a home in Greece as well.
And I wonder if he's at the point where
he's just throwing up his hands and
saying, "I give up.
I'm going to get out of here."
Yeah.
I mean I mean look, he always had to
know that this was this was not a
permanent gig. Even though he did cancel
the election.
Um
>> Yes. Yes, he did. Yeah.
But he as he says, he has no choice. I
love that. He declares martial law.
Martial law means no elections. He's
like, "Well, what can I do? My hands are
tied. Martial law."
Ridiculous.
Yeah, ridiculous.
Ridiculous is right. But you know, the
fact that that such a senior delegation
is going to Ukraine tells me that
something's up. It It looks like it
looks like
Trump is is serious about forcing this.
And um Zelenskyy realizes he just
doesn't have any more cards to play.
Hilarious if you so. But Trump ended the
Clone Wars, the Wars of Middle Earth.
>> [laughter]
>> Where's his Nobel Peace Prize? Trump
ended all the wars.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh
yeah. Uh it it's yeah. Um okay. So, do
you think So, you So, you I mean, what
do you want to care to handicap this? I
mean um
So, what what what happens next? I mean,
I would say a cease You know, Trump,
ceasefire comes first, right? So
>> to have to be kind of a cascading series
of things.
Uh you announce a ceasefire, you
announce elections, Zelenskyy leaves the
country, they have the elections, the
new parliament uh ratifies whatever deal
is made in the end, and then the thing's
finally over with Zelenskyy living in
exile with the hundreds of millions of
dollars that he's looted from the
Ukrainian treasury or from the US
government. Which is the same thing
these days.
>> Yeah. Um well, I mean so here's the
thing. Like Russia has basically been
driving a very hard bargain and I I
wonder you and I talked a little bit
about how maybe Putin wasn't really
reading Trump. I mean, I think Trump was
um I mean, he kind of missed the point.
Like Trump really wants a deal. He
doesn't care about the specific details.
Vladimir Putin, as anyone who's ever
watched him speak knows, he's all about
detail. I mean,
that that that man is like, you know,
there is not one wrinkle in his shirt,
there is not you know, every every every
I is is dotted, every T is crossed just
so. I I think maybe it was a cultural
thing that kind of like stopped us from
getting to this point. I mean, I think
Trump would have loved to just have a
broad outlines of a of a peace deal, you
know,
a year ago and then just and then just
sort of like work out the details later.
Yeah. But Russians don't roll that way.
I I think that's exactly right. And and
Trump is very much not a detail person.
>> Right.
>> All through his entire career, he's
made the the very broad, you know,
policy call, whether it was his business
policy or later on governmental policy,
and then let the underlings deal with
the details.
Um
I mean, so
I guess I'd want to answer this next
question cuz I think it's really
important for us to answer it. But also
I
while we're answering it, I mean, what's
the future for Ukraine? I mean, like
let's just say this deal goes through. I
mean, I actually think it's going to
benefit Ukraine, but um in the long run
because they are going to be rid of
their restive population in the east who
are ethnically Russian and really never
should have been in Ukraine post-1991
anyway. And they're going to have a more
culturally and politically unified
nation-state. Yeah.
Um The [clears throat]
I should add to that the the Washington
Post
it says it says the US is signaling
Zelenskyy
that if he does not sign this thing by
Thursday, Oh, wow. that
our support ends.
That's the end of it. Ends. That's huge.
>> Yeah. Well, that's why he's coming to
Jesus. Yeah. Um So, Sudva, here's the
question that I alluded to.
Are you guys pro-Ukraine or pro-Russia?
I can't tell who is more evil, Putin or
Putin or Satan. Russia's game has always
been having ethnic Russians live in
Ukraine and take over. Putin equals evil
cousin to the devil.
Uh okay. I [clears throat] Frankly, it's
not my area of expertise. I've been
clear about this for years.
I really don't
so much care for either side.
I don't really care. I'm far more
focused on the Middle East, but on on
this fight, I don't have a I don't have
a dog in this fight.
Um I look I I like I like I like
first and foremost, I'm a humanist and I
care about people and I don't and I and
I don't like unnecessary conflict. And
so toward that end, I'm always obsessed
with systems and whether systems work or
not.
Um and the the breakup of the Soviet
Union left a lot of nation-states that
didn't quite work well. And the and that
division between Ukraine and Russia
didn't work and that's why they've been
on and off again with fighting since you
know since pretty much since 2014. Um
and you know there was conflict before
that. Um
So
look, as far as I'm concerned, Russia is
an autocracy um and it's like you know,
I would not be able to thrive there
doing what I do
uh and that's a problem, you know, so um
at that said, I love the Russian people.
I like the Ukrainian people, too. Um you
know, the Ukraine has a has a has a Nazi
coddling problem. Um you know, it really
does. Uh and you know, and and I so I I
would have to say historically, I'm kind
of like as a student of World War II, I
recall the fact that you know,
Ukrainians were guarding Auschwitz and
the Red Army liberated Auschwitz. So
but it's been a long time since 1945. So
um you know, I mean what we need is for
people to get along and live in peace
side by side as much as possible. I mean
that's
that's that's that's my bias
as it is. Um and I do think also I kind
of grew up with like you did with sphere
of spheres of influence and I kind of
buy the fact that if you're a huge
country, which Russia is, you don't
really have to put up with nonsense
along your around your borders. Um you
know, if you're the US, you don't put up
with nonsense from Canada or Mexico.
Um you know, don't get too spicy. Yes,
you're a nation-state. Yes, you have
sovereignty, but
but I don't know. I I guess it's part of
it is cuz of just the way I grew up
during the Cold War.
>> During the Cold War, I'm I had the same
experience. I think that's I think
that's right.
I mean I also think like if I were the
president of Russia, here's the thing.
If I were the president of Russia, would
I have done anything differently than
Vladimir Putin even though I'm a
leftist? No. Um I I would have invaded,
too, because uh it would have been like
you guys are out of control and you're
in bed with my enemy, NATO. If if I was
uh the president of Ukraine, would I
have done what Zelensky did? No. I would
have I would have made nice. So you
know, cuz it's like you have this huge
country Yes. that used to own you Yes.
>> right next door and it's paranoid. Don't
piss them off. And yeah, Russia doesn't
What people don't understand about
Russia is they're paranoid cuz they have
no natural no natural geographical
barriers that protect their their
territory. Right. They they just have
open steps. It's plain it's easy. They
don't have giant ass mountains to
protect them or two huge oceans like we
do. That's that's the issue. That's why
they're paranoid.
Hey, we've got a a good question
from Cooper Duper 23. How common is
nepotism in intelligence, CIA, FBI,
other unknown agencies? That was always
a real beef of mine.
That it was it was a serious beef of
mine, not necessarily nepotism from
parent to child. Although you see like
entire families in the CIA, it's it's
not uncommon at all. I worked with a guy
when I first got hired, his dad was a
senior officer in the senior
intelligence service. His mom was they
were both in the Directorate of
Operations, his mom and dad and then he
got hired, then his brother got hired,
then his sister got hired. The whole
family working in the CIA. I sat next to
a guy whose uh younger brother got hired
right out right out of grad school and
then his younger sister got hired when
she finished grad school. Does would the
agency naturally trust trust you more if
you came from a a family of uh CIA
royalty like that?
>> Yeah, you have a leg up there. But I'll
tell you what I really objected to.
I remember my one of my bosses saying
"Hey, are you uh you looking forward to
the promotion panels?"
Mhm. I was up for a GS
I forget what, 13 or 14. And I said,
"No, actually, I'm not." He said, "Why
not?" I said, "Because I know they have
only six slots to promote and I know
that so-and-so, who's a member of the
promotion panel, is [__] this woman
that I'm competing against and I know
that she's going to get promoted because
he's [__] her."
I said, "I know how things work around
here." And sure enough, she got promoted
and I got passed over and then the
Deputy Director for Operations
gave me an out-of-cycle promotion cuz
I'd gotten screwed.
But that's that's what's common.
Gotcha. I've got an ad to read. Brooke
Burke, a fixture in the entertainment
and wellness industries for decades,
known for her roles in Dancing with the
Stars and Wild Wild On, is not one to
shy away from the spotlight, but shortly
after she turned 50, despite her
expertise the fitness icon suddenly
found herself battling a body that
seemed to be working against her. Now
Brooke is opening up publicly about her
experience because it's one million of
women face unexplained weight gain,
muscle loss and declining energy and
she's revealing
how she discovered one thing that made
her leaner, stronger and healthier than
ever. She says today at 53, she feels
amazing and her abs are tighter than
today than they were 10 years ago. What
changed for her was she began biohacking
and discovered she needed more protein,
but not just any protein, one specific
protein, which was a total game-changer
and when she found it, she says
it [clears throat] was like uncovering a
secret weapon for weight management and
muscle gain. Everything changed. I'm
leaner and stronger than I've been in my
whole life. She's sharing this with the
world to both so both women and men can
lean can learn all about this
revolutionary protein. Click the link in
the chat or scan the QR code on screen
in order to watch.
Um okay. Okay. Good enough. Uh
Okay, so
um any cooler talk
F U So wants to know and was there any
water cooler talk at the CIA about
aliens and alien craft retrieval? No.
>> [laughter]
>> No, nothing.
Nothing. We always figured that was the
Pentagon's bailiwick.
John, you want to take a critical
comment? Sure.
>> You're you're a big boy, right? I'm a
big boy. I can take it. Here we go. So
it's up on YouTube. I like John in
general. This is from Light Fixing, but
his apologetics for I guess apologism
for Russia is [__] pathetic. How can
you be against Israel's aggression and
not Russia's no Are you crazy?
Listen, on the morning of the Russian
invasion of Ukraine, I said on my radio
show on a Russian [__] network
and these were my exact words, "I
unreservedly condemn the Russian
invasion of Ukraine and I urge Russian
troops to leave Ukrainian territory
immediately."
So don't give me this nonsense about
being pro-Russian.
Cuz that's what it is. It's nonsense.
>> I've known John for years and I I just
don't think there's any credibility any
any grounds for that for that
>> That's outrageous. Um Evil Robot Army,
thanks for the $5 over on YouTube. John,
did you ever interact with NRO? Is it
common for people to move between the
letter agencies or do careers tend to
stay in one agency and maybe explain
>> Also also a good question. NRO is the
National Reconnaissance Office.
Um they uh they manage and interpret the
overhead photography from from our uh
satellite system.
Uh it was very common actually for us to
liaise with NRO or for NRO analysts to
transfer over to the CIA
to the Directorate of Intelligence. My
second wife actually began her career as
an NRO analyst.
Um it it is
I'm going to say not uncommon for people
to transfer from NSA to CIA or from FBI
to CIA, occasionally from DIA to CIA,
but it's very very rare for CIA officers
to go somewhere else because we had this
idea that we were the we were the top of
the heap. And if you were to go to any
other um agency, it was a step down.
I did work with a guy, he was a young
branch chief when I was a new analyst
um and he he got passed over for a GS-15
and and left in a fit of pique
and went over to the Pentagon
and within five years was the Assistant
Secretary of of Defense for POW/MIA
Affairs. So that that worked out very
well for him, but otherwise
yeah, it's not uncommon for for other
agencies to transfer to the CIA. It's
highly uncommon to go from CIA to other
I think only a small fraction of 1% of
of Americans even know that there are
other intelligence agencies beside the
CIA and if you count them, the FBI.
Yeah. Or NSA.
Um
and there's so many. Um this I love this
question. Thank you so much, Hamza.
John, what was the reaction of your
parents when you joined the agency?
Oh, my parents were beside themselves
with worry.
My parents had this vision of the agency
from like, you know,
James Bond movies or something.
Um
I I did have to tell my dad at one
point. I was stationed in Athens and and
my dad
like stood up in church one Sunday and
announced that I was an undercover CIA
officer in Athens. So, if anybody needed
any help in the American Embassy there,
they could just call me. And so, one day
all these people from church in
Newcastle, Pennsylvania started calling
me at my desk in the station in Athens
asking for help getting their relatives
visas. And I'm like, what the [__] is
going on here?
And so, I called my mom and she's like,
I told him I told him not to say
anything. I said, "Dad, I said you're
going to get me killed.
I'm undercover here. It's a critical
threat for terrorism post. Nobody is
supposed to know that I'm in the CIA. If
word leaks out and now it's out,
I could get killed. I said, "What are
you doing?"
And so, every person who called I had to
say, "My dad
has a touch of dementia. I'm not with
the CIA. He doesn't know what he's
talking about." And then finally it just
kind of died a quiet death.
>> [laughter]
>> Parents can really [__] you up. He was
so proud of me that he just that came
out with it in church.
Oh my god, that's so funny. That's like
my mom
on my very first book signing
for my very first book
she bum rushed the stage like she was at
a Run-DMC concert and basically like,
"I'm his mom. I'M SO PROUD." [laughter]
YOU KNOW WHAT? MY COLLEGE ROOMMATE,
Eddie Harwitz,
Eddie got an internship with Senator
Tom Harkin,
progressive Democrat from Iowa. And his
mom and stepdad came to Washington and
he scheduled a courtesy call on Senator
Harkin. And Tom Harkin was just the
loveliest guy in the world. You know,
just a sweet guy. His power authority
never went to his head. So, he was very
happy to meet Eddie's mom and stepdad.
So, he he took them to Harkin's office
and Harkin says, "You know, Eddie works
so hard for us and he worked on the
campaign and we're really appreciative
of all the things that he does for us
here in the office." And she says she
goes like this to Eddie. She goes like
this she says, "All I want is that he
should be a good boy."
>> [laughter]
>> And he's like, "Mom."
I'll never forget it. That's so awesome.
>> [laughter]
>> I I'm really I really love this question
from Faraz Matar.
Um this I have a lot to say about this,
but you should go first because of that,
John. Faraz Matar is asking, "Is the
POW/MIA
that black iconic flag the
same thing? I've always heard that was
disinformation like John Birch or
LaRouche stuff?" Yes. Um that we had no
soldiers left in Vietnam.
That's yes.
>> Ah, I see. I I have always found it very
very hard to believe
that we have anybody in in Vietnam.
We did.
>> Very hard to believe. I mean, that flag
is still in front of US post offices.
It's It's
It's all over the country. It's It's all
You know, you see it everywhere, right?
And there's that image of like the
watchtower
you know, with like the By the way, if
you look carefully, the guard has the
little you know,
this Vietnamese peasant pointy
Vietnamese peasant hat like in the
watchtower. And
And you know, and and the and it's it's
not the
It's the MIA aspect. And I mean, there
certainly are MIAs, right? But like
they're conflating POWs and the
implication is that there are Americans
being held like Rambo 37
in
you know, somewhere by the dirty commies
like in the rice paddies. Right. By the
gooks. It's
It's not true. It's like And and like
you know,
Vietnam is lousy with American tourists.
I I would think at some point, you know,
American tourists would have like been
backpacking through the jungle and would
have been like, "Oh, LOOK AT THAT POW
CAMP." YES. Not to mention these [__]
would be like 80 years old now.
Um
I mean, it the whole thing is it but it
it feeds into this victim narrative that
like really makes you know, that really
drives a lot of American politics. Like
everyone's picking on us. You know,
we're the victims of injustice and it's
just all deflection and distraction from
the reality which is that it's the exact
opposite.
Yes, indeed. I I just have never I've
never believed it. Now, if they went out
into the jungle and started doing a dig,
might they stumble upon, you know, bones
or bone fragments? Of course. Of course.
Yeah. Yeah, no no. Hey Ted. Ted,
breaking news. Sophia Negroponte, the
the daughter of former DNI John
Negroponte,
was convicted again of murder
after killing her boyfriend.
I I I think we've talked about this in
the past. Sophia Negroponte, I'll tell
you I I met I met her when she was 6
years old. When I worked for John
Negroponte at the United Nations, he was
the ambassador to the United Nations
during George W. Bush. She was just a
little girl. The ambassador and Mrs.
Negroponte had adopted Sophia and her
sister from Honduras.
Um they were like six and four when I
met them.
She grew up. She's 32 now. She grew up
to have a very serious drinking problem.
And she Several years ago she was drunk
and at a mutual friend's home with her
boyfriend in Rockville, Maryland. They
got into an argument and she stabbed him
in the neck.
Um and she killed him. [__] She She
went to the kitchen, took out a knife
and stabbed him in the neck and killed
him. And then
her housemates called 911. The cops
came. She said that she didn't realize
what she was doing, but she did it. She
confessed. She did it. I'm so sorry. I
shouldn't have done it. They arrested
her. They charged her with um
with second-degree murder. She was
convicted and sentenced to life in
prison.
Then she appealed
and she won the appeal.
It was something about jury
instructions. Mhm. And so, the trial
restarted 2 weeks ago. This time her
attorneys offered up DNA evidence said
saying that she did not stab him. That
it wasn't her DNA on the knife. It was
somebody else's DNA. But then everybody
else in the house said, "No, she jumped
on him. She knocked him down. She sat on
his chest and she stabbed him in the
neck with the knife."
And so, just now she was convicted
again. Okay. And she's facing again life
without parole.
What a bizarre story. Bizarre. And
Ambassador Negroponte,
it says now he's 86 years old. He and
his wife Diana
sat in the first row of the courtroom
every single day. This trial and the
previous trial. They're heartbroken. I
last saw her I was invited to a
Christmas party at his house in like
8 or 9. I think it was 8.
And I I haven't seen I haven't seen them
since, but
yeah, this is going to be tough for
anybody. No doubt.
>> Wow. Um I'm being asked by Ali,
"Why don't I do mini podcasts and such?"
You want some of mine?
I've got five today. Well, I don't Yeah,
I mean, I'm It's like It's like the
rules of being a vampire. You have to be
invited. Um so, if people invite me, you
know, I will go. But if I'm not invited,
I'm not I'm not going to go. Um
yeah, whatever.
Uh
so,
you know,
let's see here.
Oh, Toby, thank you for the $2. Can I
share more about my master class? Yes,
I'm going to send out another
announcement today on Substack and I'm
going to put it on Twitter as well. I'll
put it on Facebook, too. So, I'm doing a
surveillance and surveillance detection
class, but we're extending it to eight
different pods. I'll do three on
surveillance and surveillance detection
and we're going to do five on
cybersecurity and how to protect
yourself and your computer systems.
We're doing it in conjunction with
Bay Path University in Massachusetts.
So, I'll send I'll send more information
out today.
Thanks for asking.
>> Okay.
John, should we talk about this FBI
story?
Yeah, let's talk about the FBI story.
This is nuts.
So, the So, basically
insider inside the inside the bureau is
accusing the internal counterespionage
cell. Correct me if I'm wrong, but
that's that seems like the
the counterintelligence
branch, right?
>> It's exactly what it is. Yeah.
>> To make sure that there that there's no
one working against America and the FBI
within the FBI. No Robert Hansens.
It turns out that they have a
quote-unquote executive exemption that
prevents
that cell from looking into fraud
allegations of fraud, retaliation, or
espionage even if there's a credible tip
that comes in from another US government
agency.
The They've been Anybody who's who's
tried to violate this rule
has been punished and uh, and basically
retaliated against, ironically. Um,
and uh, and so this is starting to break
now in the Washington Examiner and other
right-wing media places. It's so far not
getting much traction
in democratically aligned uh, stuff. And
of course, obviously you think right
away about Robert Hanssen.
After following Robert Hanssen, how
could there be an exception for anyone
up to and including the director?
>> Right?
So, Brian Kelley was a friend of mine at
the CIA. He was a senior officer in the
CIA's Counterintelligence Center. Robert
Hanssen accused Brian of being the mole
in the US government. We knew that there
was a second mole after Aldrich Ames was
uh, was arrested. And Brian was not just
suspended from the CIA, um, he was
threatened with with the death penalty.
And his daughter was threatened with
arrest if she wouldn't rat out her
father. Well, Brian was completely
innocent. The mole was actually Hanssen
Hanssen himself.
And so finally,
Hanssen, who was the head of the FBI's
mole hunting unit,
was arrested for being the mole and
sentenced to life without parole. He
died two years ago in his steel bunk in
the supermax in Florence, uh, Colorado.
So, we know from history
that
Russian moles or Chinese moles or or
Cuban or Israeli or whomever
can be in the FBI just as easily as they
can be in the CIA or the Navy or
wherever they happen to be.
If what this whistleblower is telling us
is true,
this has to be dealt with swiftly and
harshly.
Um, and the way things like this have
been said
>> true. It's obviously true because
>> to be true. Because I mean, I'm a
student of of of official corporate and
government denials, right? Well, so the
absence of a denial here means that it's
true. I mean, there's no denial at all,
right? They're not saying, "That's not
true. We don't have such an exception."
Right.
Right. I mean, by definition, it's true.
By definition, it is true. We know
historically that it is true.
Yeah, and it makes perfect sense and
it's like
I mean, it's just it's incredible
though. I mean, it's like nobody learns
from history.
I mean,
Nobody learns from history. If Hanssen
gets access to the news in prison, he's
got to be laughing his ass off. Yeah.
And Nicholson,
get this. There was this [__] I used
to work with in the Counterterrorism
Center named Nicholson.
And when
when Aldrich Ames got caught, it never
occurred to Nicholson
A, that there was another mole, or B,
that the CIA had moles in the KGB. So,
Nicholson was pissed off that he'd been
passed over for promotion. So, he
volunteered to the KGB to be a mole for
them in the CIA.
And he outed more than 120
uh, undercover CIA officers to the KGB,
all of whom had to be, as they say,
brought in from the cold, so they could
no longer be undercover.
Um, Nicholson was caught,
was sentenced to 30 years.
He did the 30
and he got out.
So, he's like living high on the hog now
here in the Washington area like
everything's perfectly fine. But to make
matters worse,
when he was in prison, he asked his son
to go visit him.
And when his son went to visit him, I
think it was in Oregon. He was in a
federal prison in Oregon.
Um, he gave his son this list of
additional names that he had thought of.
And he told his son, "Give these names
to the KGB and they'll give you some
money and hold the money so that when
I'm released, I'll have a little nest
egg to come home to." Oh my god. And the
FBI caught the son. Well, did they just
search him like at at prison or or did
the or did the son decide it? Or did the
son decide to do this?
>> you can't pass stuff back and forth. The
son was an idiot. He was going to do it.
Uh, but the FBI caught him. And so they
added like five years or seven years
onto Nicholson's uh, prison term. So
unrepentant.
>> So, totally unrepentant. Total traitor.
Unbelievable.
>> Uh-huh.
Yeah, you can't make this stuff up.
>> [laughter]
>> I I I do kind of I mean, I do kind of
admire people who have the strength of
their uh,
of their of their corrupt convictions.
[laughter]
It's like it's like well, I mean, he
it's like I know what I am and this is
what I do. It's hilarious.
Um, yeah. Oh my god, that's fantastic.
Um,
how does military intelligence work?
Paul wants to know. Oh, well, that's a
good question, too. Military
intelligence is normally very specific
to order of battle intelligence.
Uh, you know, I I half-jokingly say all
the time that my eyes would just glaze
over when these guys would start their
order of battle uh, briefing. What order
of battle means is they'll say,
"Elements of the first army corps are
located here on the map and elements of
the, you know, this this group are over
here and then this
platoon is positioned here to move north
and 13 km and
none of that means anything to me." You
and I are so wired the same way. Like in
>> [laughter]
>> like in history,
I hate military histories. Hate it.
Like, you know, like, "Oh, then the
pincer movement and you know, like
>> It's a traditional flanking movement. I
don't
care.
I don't care.
Yeah.
It's it's just not for me. But that's
what they focus on. The the bigger
>> [laughter]
>> Phil Chads, hilarious. That makes my
day. Andrew Bustamante found all the
moles.
>> [laughter]
>> That's great.
But anyway, yeah, this this military
analysis intelligence analysis it it it
it means nothing to me.
I thank god we have guys who love it.
Well, yeah.
>> Because it's important. It is important.
No new questions. Look, military history
is important. Yeah. I mean, obviously.
Uh, yeah, it's just like, you know, when
I just cuz I'm not interested in
something, doesn't mean that it's not
inherently interesting. You know. That's
right.
Although there are things that I think
I'm not interested in and I think no one
should be interested in, like curling.
Why would you be into curling? I don't
understand.
>> like that. It's it looks very um,
relaxing to me. But also, there are a
couple of guys from my church, guys my
age, you know, pot bellies, and uh, they
they
went to the Greek Embassy and they said,
"Listen, we're all Greek-Americans. We
want to we want to create the Greek
Olympic curling uh, team." And so they
did in the last Winter Olympics four
years ago. And so all these all these,
you know, 50-year-old guys from church,
they're doing curling. They didn't do
well. They came in like eighth or ninth.
But by god, they made it to the
Olympics.
I I was so happy to watch them on TV. It
made me very proud.
>> We have a quick Robbie announcement and
then we're we're closing up and moving
on to the TMI show. Here we go. Robbie,
you have an announcement for us.
Okay, quick announcement. Y'all have
been asking for it. Now you're going to
get it. Y'all are going to be getting a
a deprogrammed merch store. It will be
going live next week.
Uh,
it'll go live on YouTube first. I will
work on the way to make it go live over
on Rumble. So, you wanted it. Now you're
going to get it. Awesome.
>> And we're coming up with all kinds of
things and it's a good thing I'm that
we're friends with the graphic artist.
That makes this easier.
Yes, I've heard I've heard that we know
a guy like that. Thanks, Robbie. Thank
you, Robbie.
>> Please like, follow, and share the show.
We're going to be back here tomorrow.
Uh, no, we're going to be back here
Monday.
Monday through Friday, so we have the
weekend off. It feels like
I don't even know what to do with that.
Um, anyway, 9:00 a.m. Eastern time
Monday morning. Be here or be square.
We'll be here all next week. Well, well,
we'll figure out what we're doing about
Thanksgiving. I guess we probably won't
be here Thanksgiving. Um, but we'll
we'll we'll work all that out and then
let you know what's up with that. But
we'll be here Monday. Um, thanks and
please stay tuned for the TMI show with
Ted Rall and Manila Chan. That's half of
that is me and we'll stay right here. If
you're in the Rumble room, it'll just
happen automatically cuz it's weird like
that. Um, anyway, uh, take care, John.
Nice seeing you. You You too, Ted. Have
a good weekend. You too.
>> [music]